Welcome, in the last lecture, we finally finished the implementation of our left foot IK.
欢迎，在上一讲中，我们终于完成了我们的左脚IK的实现。
Now when we are climbing, the tip of our left foot will be snapped to the climbable surface.
现在，当我们攀爬时，我们的左脚尖将被卡在可攀爬的表面上。
And this is great.
而这是很好的。
Now we have the left foot ready.
现在我们的左脚已经准备好了。
Next thing, I am going to take care of the right foot.
接下来，我将处理右脚的问题。
So double click to open my control rack.
所以双击来打开我的控制架。
All we need to do next is to repeat this process for our foot_r.
我们接下来要做的就是对我们的脚_r重复这个过程。
So I am going to go to the top of it.
所以我要去到它的顶部。
I am going to select this function and duplicate it.
我将选择这个函数并复制它。
Connect this pin to here.
把这个引脚连接到这里。
And change this one from IK foot_l to IK foot_r.
把这个从IK foot_l改成IK foot_r。
And give it the same target location offset.
并给它同样的目标位置偏移。
I am going to promote the return value of it to a variable.
我将把它的返回值提升为一个变量。
Name this one to foot_r_target_offset.
把这个命名为foot_r_target_offset。
And connect this pin to here.
并将这个引脚连接到这里。
And next thing, I am going to drag out this target offset.
接下来，我将拖出这个目标偏移。
Click set it.
点击设置它。
And connect this one to here.
并把这个连接到这里。
So we will also be resetting this value.
所以我们也将重新设置这个值。
And the second thing, we need to interpolate it.
第二件事，我们需要对它进行插值。
So drag out this value, select it.
所以拖出这个值，选择它。
And select this interpolate node, duplicate it.
然后选择这个插值节点，复制它。
Connect it to this target B.
把它连接到这个目标B。
And promote the return value of it into another variable.
并把它的返回值提升到另一个变量中。
I am going to rename this to foot_r_current_offset.
我将把它重命名为foot_r_current_offset。
And drag out this current offset, get it.
然后拖出这个当前偏移，得到它。
Plug it into socket A.
把它插入插座A。
For the interpreting speed here, I am going to give it the same value as this one.
对于这里的解释速度，我将给它一个与这个相同的值。
So connect this one to here.
所以把这个连接到这里。
Add the read-run node.
添加读运行的节点。
Move it down a bit.
把它往下移一点。
And connect this pin to here.
然后把这个引脚连接到这里。
All right.
好了。
That's the offset ready and next thing, I am going to modify its transform.
这就是准备好的偏移量，接下来，我将修改它的变换。
So right mouse button click, type in modify transform.
所以鼠标右键点击，输入修改变换。
Hey, this is me from the future.
嘿，这就是来自未来的我。
One thing that I noticed from 5.1 is if we duplicate the null modify transform in here,
我注意到5.1版本中的一件事是，如果我们在这里重复空的修改变换、
for some reason that will cause some unexpected behavior for this node.
出于某种原因，这将导致这个节点的一些意外行为。
And later we won't be able to see the expected read result when we click play.
而且以后我们在点击播放时将无法看到预期的读取结果。
Hopefully when you are watching this, it is already fixed.
希望你在看这个的时候，它已经被修复了。
And if it is not, just make sure you don't duplicate this node and bring it out manually
如果没有，请确保你不要重复这个节点，并且每次都手动把它拿出来。
every time.
每次都是如此。
All right.
好了。
Back to the OME.
回到OME。
And change the mode into additive global.
把模式改为全局加法。
In the drop down here, I am going to select a new bone.
在这里的下拉菜单中，我将选择一个新的骨头。
So it will be ik_foot_r.
所以它将是ik_foot_r。
Connect this pin to here.
把这个针脚连接到这里。
And I am going to drag out this foot_r_current_offset, get it.
我将拖出这个foot_r_current_offset，得到它。
I am going to connect this pin to the translation.
我将把这个针脚连接到翻译上。
All right.
好的。
And the last thing will be this foot_body_ik.
最后是这个foot_body_ik。
So click this button to add another element into this effectors.
所以点击这个按钮，把另一个元素添加到这个效应器中。
I am going to select this null, duplicate it, change it to ik_foot_r.
我将选择这个空，复制它，把它改为ik_foot_r。
And plug this transform into it.
然后把这个变换插入其中。
Select the bone, change this to foot_r.
选择这个骨头，把它改成foot_r。
And that's pretty much it.
这就差不多了。
I am going to click compile.
我将会点击编译。
And you can see I have a warning here for the compilation.
你可以看到我在这里有一个编译的警告。
So I am going to go to my output log.
所以我要去看我的输出日志。
And here it says can parse default value.
这里说可以解析默认值。
And this is the default value for our current and target offset.
这是我们当前和目标偏移量的默认值。
This is actually a false alarm.
这实际上是一个假警报。
We don't need to worry about that.
我们不需要担心这个问题。
So to get rid of this issue, you can move up to here and click this add button to add
所以为了摆脱这个问题，你可以移到这里，点击这个添加按钮来添加
a new variable, change its type.
一个新的变量，改变其类型。
And drag it out.
然后把它拖出来。
Select get it.
选择得到它。
Plug it into here.
把它插入这里。
And click compile again.
然后再点击编译。
You can see that warning is gone.
你可以看到那个警告已经消失了。
I am going to delete this value and I am going to delete this variable.
我将删除这个值，我将删除这个变量。
Alright, click compile again.
好的，再次点击编译。
And I am going to test this.
我将测试这个。
So go back to my level, go back to my content browser.
所以回到我的水平，回到我的内容浏览器。
I am going to click play in here.
我将在这里点击播放。
And I am going to try to climb up.
我将尝试往上爬。
So this is working for my right foot.
所以这对我的右脚是有效的。
I am going to try to move a bit.
我将尝试移动一下。
So 18 units also works for right foot I think.
所以18个单位也适用于右脚，我想。
Maybe it's a bit much when we are climbing.
也许我们在爬的时候，这有点多。
So I am going to try lowering it down to maybe 16.5.
所以我将尝试把它降低到16.5。
And click compile, go back to my level.
然后点击编译，回到我的水平。
I am going to try again.
我将再试一次。
Alright something like that.
好吧，就这样吧。
You can tweak this offset value however you like.
你可以随心所欲地调整这个偏移值。
I think 16.5 works when we are climbing.
我认为16.5在我们爬坡的时候是有效的。
And just like that, our right foot IK is working as expected.
就这样，我们的右脚IK就像预期的那样工作了。
And it's time for our challenge today.
现在是我们今天的挑战时间。
So the challenge is handle right foot IK in your control rig.
所以挑战是在你的控制装置中处理右脚IK。
All you need to do now is to repeat the process that we did for our left foot IK.
你现在需要做的就是重复我们对左脚IK的处理过程。
And this shouldn't be something too complicated to do.
这不应该是太复杂的事情。
Feel free to refer back to the video if you need help.
如果你需要帮助，可以随时回看视频。
Alright, pause the video now and give this a go.
好了，现在暂停视频，试试这个。
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
我们在下一节课上见。
Bye for now.
暂时再见。